jobs4.co.uk 2019-12-27

# Jobs4.co.uk Privacy Policy

                  Jobs4.co.uk Privacy Policy – updated 1st April 2018
Jobs4.co.uk is a global online job board business that operates online job portals to accurately match
candidates with companies. Jobs4.co.uk works closely with its sister websites Jobs.co.uk and
thejobsportal.co.uk, all owned and operating under Jobs4UK Ltd. When you submit information to
Jobs4.co.uk , your information will also be shared with Jobs.co.uk, which will also use your information in
accordance with this Privacy Policy. Jobs4.co.uk will remain responsible for the management and security of
jointly used Personal Information that you submit to Jobs4.co.uk.
We take data protection very seriously and understand the importance of protecting your privacy and
Personal Information. "Personal Information" is information that identifies you as an individual such as your
name, date of birth, email address, IP address and CV.
How do we collect information from you?
We collect and use your Personal Information in accordance with this our Privacy Policy. The majority of the
Personal Information you provide to us freely when you give us your CV or job cover letter to a job
application.
Please do not submit such Personal Information to us if you do not wish us to collect it.
However, please be aware, some Personal Information may include information you voluntarily, but
unintentionally provided to us (for example, if you express preferences regarding searches for jobs related to
trade unions).
We also collect from:
• our websites (the "Websites");
• the software applications made available by us for use on or through computers and mobile devices (the
"Apps");
• cookies ("Cookies");
• publically available information; and
• other tools and applications (our "Online Content").
What Personal Information do we collect?
Personal Information we collect about you may include the following:
• General identification and contact information: your name; address; email; IP address; telephone details;
gender; marital status; family status; date and place of birth; physical attributes including photos
• Other sensitive information: trade union membership, religious beliefs, political opinions or racial or ethical
origin, and criminal record.
• Information enabling us to provide products and services: age, location, whether or not you hold a driving
licence that enable identification of job search (for example, post code or job role)
• Marketing preferences: enter a contest or prize draw or other sales promotion, or respond to a voluntary
customer satisfaction survey
Terms of Use                                                                                       May 2018

• Statistical information: aggregate statistical information about site visitors and users for internal use and for
other lawful purposes eg. Salary averages. We provide this information to customers, advertisers, suppliers
and other reputable third parties. Where we provide such information we will provide this in an anonymous
format and not include any Personal Information.
• Information from Apps: submit comments to the Site, participate in message boards, blogs, send us emails
or any other user generated content facility
• Publically available information in relation to professional history: educational background; employment
history; skills and experience; professional licenses and affiliations; educational and professional
qualifications
What legal basis do we rely on to process your Personal Information?
• Consent
On some occasions, Jobs4.co.uk processes your data with your consent. For example, we rely on consent
when we send promotional material or when you link your Jobs4.co.uk account to your Social Network
account. You have the right to withdraw consent at any time. Where consent is the only legal basis for
processing, we will cease to process data after consent is withdrawn.
• The processing is necessary to fulfil a contract
Jobs4.co.uk may process your data when we need to do this to fulfil a contract with you, such as to send
your CV to an employer or recruiter for a specific job application.
• Legitimate Interest
Jobs4.co.uk also processes your data when it is in our legitimate interests to do this and when these
interests are not overridden by your data protection rights.
Our legitimate interests include:
• ensuring the security and integrity of our Services and in ensuring that our Websites and Apps operate
effectively;
• selling and supplying goods and services to our customers;
• protecting customers, employees and other individuals and maintaining their safety, health and welfare;
• promoting, marketing and advertising our products and services;
• sending promotional communications which are relevant and tailored to individual customers;
• understanding our customers’ behaviour, activities, preferences, and needs;
• improving existing products and services and developing new products and services;
• handling customer contacts, queries, complaints or disputes; and
• fulfilling our duties to our customers, colleagues, shareholders and other stakeholders.
Terms of Use                                                                                         May 2018

• the processing is necessary because of a legal obligation that applies
Jobs4.co.uk may process your data to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations eg preventing,
investigating and detecting crime, fraud or anti-social behaviour and prosecuting offenders, including working
with law enforcement agencies
Who do we share your Personal Information with?
Jobs4.co.uk may make Personal Information available to:
• Our group companies
We are a member company of Axel Springer GmbH. We may share your personal data with certain
members of our group companies which also operate online job portals. Where they have access to your
personal data they will use it only for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. Jobs4.co.uk will remain
responsible for the management and security of jointly used Personal Information. Access to Personal
Information within Jobs4.co.uk , and our group of companies, is restricted to those individuals who have a
need to access the information for our business purposes.
• Recruiters and other agents
In the course of our business to help you search for and get a job, Jobs4.co.uk may make Personal
Information available to third parties such as recruiters and other intermediaries and agents and other
business partners.
• Our service providers
This includes external third-party service providers, such as accountants, auditors, experts, lawyers and
other outside professional advisors; IT systems, support and hosting service providers; printing, advertising,
marketing and market research and analysis service providers; document and records management
providers; technical engineers; data storage and cloud providers and similar third-party vendors and
outsourced service providers that assist us in carrying out business activities.
• Governmental authorities and third parties involved in court action
Jobs4.co.uk may share Personal Information with governmental or other public authorities (including, but not
limited to, workers’ compensation boards, courts, law enforcement, tax authorities and criminal investigations
agencies); and third-party civil legal process participants and their accountants, auditors, lawyers and other
advisors and representatives as we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (a) to comply with applicable
law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to
requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your
country of residence; (d) to enforce our terms and conditions; (e) to protect our operations or those of any of
our group companies; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and that of our group companies,
you or others; and (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit our damages.
• Other third parties
Occasionally, we may share Personal Information with other third parties. We will always do this under
contract and in accordance with your instructions.
Terms of Use                                                                                      May 2018

How we use Personal Information?
We use Personal Information to do some or all of the following:
• Communicate with you as part of our business;
• Send you important information regarding changes to our policies, other terms and conditions, the
Jobs4.co.uk Website and App and other administrative information;
• Provide improved quality, training and security and manage other commercial risks;
• Carry out market research and analysis, including satisfaction surveys;
• Provide marketing information to you (including information about other products and services offered by
selected third-party partners) in accordance with preferences you have expressed. Please be aware you can
always change these at My Account;
• Personalise your experience on the Jobs4.co.uk Website and App by presenting information and
advertisements tailored to you;
• Allow you to participate in contests, prize draws and similar promotions, and to administer these activities.
Some of these activities have additional terms and conditions, which could contain additional information
about how we use and disclose your Personal Information, so we suggest that you read these carefully;
• Facilitate social media sharing functionality;
• Manage our infrastructure and business operations, and comply with internal policies and procedures,
including those relating to auditing; finance and accounting; billing and collections; IT systems; data and
website hosting; business continuity; and records, document and print management;
• Resolve complaints, and handle requests for data access or correction;
• Comply with applicable laws and regulatory obligations (including laws outside your country of residence),
such as those relating to anti-money laundering and anti-terrorism; comply with legal process; and respond
to requests from public and governmental authorities (including those outside your country of residence);
• Establish and defend legal rights; protect our operations or those of any of our group companies or
insurance business partners, our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our group companies, you
or others; and pursue available remedies or limit our damages.
International Transfers of Personal Information
Personal Information which you supply to us is generally stored and kept inside the European Economic
Area.
However, due to the nature of our global business and the technologies required, your Personal Information
may be transferred to third party service providers outside the EEA, in countries where there may be a lower
legal level of data protection. In such situations, we transfer the minimum amount of data necessary,
anonymise it where possible and enter legal contracts to aim to ensure these third parties handle your
Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the European levels of data protection.
Terms of Use                                                                                      May 2018

How can you manage or delete Personal Information?
When you access our website online, we store some information about you. This is anonymous and used for
statistical purposes.
When you create an account and log-in to your 'My Account' area, it is protected by your password and may
only be accessed by you. You can manage the content and information in your Account at any time, by
logging in to your "My Account".
Your CV can be viewed by Jobs4.co.uk customers. Further, when your profile is searchable your application
activity (eg. number of applications, job titles, locations & salaries) will be visible to Jobs4.co.uk customers.
This is also the default setting.
Please note that Jobs4.co.uk reserves the right to remove from our database, CVs which include any content
that we consider to be illegal or offensive. We will respect the choices you make to limit sharing or visibility
settings in your "My Account".
You can de-activate or delete your account at any time, make your profile anonymous or choose to not make
your profile searchable. To de-activate, please go to your "My Account".
However, if you would like to permanently delete your account, you can send an email to our Data Protection
Officer (DPO) (see below) with the subject line "Permanently delete my information and account". Please do
not forget to tell us who you are.
Security
Jobs4.co.uk is committed to keeping your personal data safe and secure from unauthorised access to or
unauthorised alterations, disclosure or destruction of information that we hold.
Our security measures include: -
• encryption of our services and data;
• review our information collection, storage and processing practices, including physical security measures;
• restrict access to personal access to personal information to Jobs4.co.uk employees, contractors and
agents who need to know that information in order to process it for us and who are subject to contractual
confidentiality and processing obligations. They may be disciplined or their contract terminated if they fail to
meet these obligations; and
• internal policies setting out our data security approach and training for employees.
Additional Services for Website and App
• Location based services
If you use the Jobs4.co.uk App we will ask you if you want to use our geolocation service. This service is
provided by Adobe Systems Software Ireland Limited. Based on your mobile phone GPS signal it allows us
to identify your location. We will use this information to provide you with job offers close to you and to
improve our Products and Services. In no case will we merge such information with any personally
identifiable information. We will at no times be able to connect you personally in connection with the
Terms of Use                                                                                         May 2018

respective location. You may at any stage opt out of location tracking by changing the App settings.
However, you will also lose the location supported product functionality as well.
For further information about Adobe and their service please visit: http://www.adobe.com/privacy.html.
• Push notifications
If you use the Jobs4.co.uk Website or App, you may also consent to push notifications, text messages,
alerts, emails or other types of messages directly sent to you outside or inside of the Jobs4.co.uk App to
your mobile device or desktop browser. If you declare your consent to receive such messages a device
token will be generated, which will be associated with your device.
You can opt out from receiving such messages by changing the settings of your device.
• Online drives
If you enable us, we access the following Services for the limited purpose of helping us to upload or
otherwise access your CV, cover letters or any other documents you provide us to assist you apply for jobs.
The Services we use are:
• Google Cloud
• OneDrive
• DropBox
We will ask for your consent before using information for any purpose other.
Marketing and Advertising
• Online Behavioural Advertising
We partner with third-party advertising networks so that we and other advertisers can display advertising
which is more relevant to you and your interests on our Web site or on other sites that you visit and assess
the performance of that advertising. We and our ad network partners may utilise cookies or web beacons
along with other codes such as your Identifier for Advertising (IFA) or Android ID for your phone to better
understand your interests from the web pages you interact with and the search terms you use on our site to
build a picture of the category of interests or preferences you have and to provide advertisements about
goods and services that may be of interest to you. Our ad network partners do not collect and do not have
access to any information from which you can be directly identified such as your real name or address or
email. They may, however, anonymously track your Internet usage across other websites in their networks
beyond these Sites. To learn more about the use of this information or to choose not to receive tailored
advertising by opting out, you can visit either the Network Advertising Initiative at networkadvertising.org or
the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance (EDAA) at http://www.youronlinechoices.com or visit
the privacy statements of our partners: Google, Adobe and Tealium. You can also learn more about our
use of cookies and similar technologies and your choices by reading our cookies policy. Please note that if
you opt-out you will continue to receive generic advertising that has not been targeted to you and your
interests.
Terms of Use                                                                                     May 2018

Your Rights
You have the following rights:
• the right to ask what personal data that we hold about you at any time, subject to a fee specified by law
(currently £10);
• the right to ask us to update and correct any out-of-date or incorrect personal data that we hold about you
free of charge; and
• (as set out above) the right to opt out of any marketing communications that we may send you.
If you wish to exercise any of the above rights, please contact us using the contact details set out below.
Children and minors
Jobs4.co.uk is not directed towards individuals under the age of eighteen (18), however we are aware due to
the nature of some of the job offerings, those between 14 and 18 may use the Services.
Individuals under the age of thirteen (13) are expressly prohibited from using Jobs4.co.uk Website and App,
unless parental consent is provided and we are notified.
Third Party Privacy Practices
This Privacy Policy does not address, and we are not responsible for, the privacy, information or other
practices of any third parties to which the Jobs4.co.uk website and App link. The inclusion of a link on the
Website or App does not imply endorsement of the linked site or service by us or by Jobs4.co.uk. Please
note that we are not responsible for the collection, usage and disclosure policies and practices (including the
data security practices) of other organisations or any other software application developer or provider, social
media platform, operating system or wireless service provider, or device manufacturer, including any
Personal Information you disclose to other organisations through or in connection with the Apps or our Social
Media Pages.
Please note that although we require customers who use our services, such as employers seeking to recruit
staff, to agree to use the information made available solely for recruitment-related purposes, we do not
control their use of any information that they have access to as part of receiving our services. Please be
aware your current employer may be a customer of Jobs4.co.uk , or a client of one of our job boards in our
group. Although it is a requirement of our Contract and Terms and Conditions of Jobs4.co.uk and other job
boards not to use Personal Information for any purpose other than to obtain a job, we cannot restrict the
customers who access profiles on our database and cannot be held responsible for any eventuality. As part
of the registration process Jobs4.co.uk offers you the option of remaining anonymous.
If you opt-in to Job Alerts, you will receive your Job Alerts from our third-party partner: Austinshire Partners
LLC. World HQ is at: 8760-A Research Boulevard #133, Austin, Texas, TX 78758
Terms of Use                                                                                       May 2018

Who to contact about your Personal Information
The data controller responsible for your information is Jobs4.co.uk .
If you have any questions about this policy or our use of your Personal Information you can email:
paul@jobs4.co.uk or write to the Data Protection Officer, Jobs4UK Ltd. Network House, Hagley Road,
Edgbaston, Birmingham. B16 8LB. If you do not think we are handling your Personal Information adequately,
you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office. Further information,
including contact details, are available at https://ico.org.uk
Changes to Privacy Policy
We review this Privacy Policy regularly and reserve the right to make changes at any time to take account of
changes in our business and legal requirements. We will place updates on our website.
Please take a look at the "Effective From" date at the top of this Privacy Policy to see when it was last
revised.
The Site is operated by Jobs4UK Ltd. Network House, Hagley Road, Edgbaston, Birmingham. B16 8LB.
Registered number: 07067723. Registered address is at Meriden Hall, Main Road, Meriden, Warwickshire,
CV7 7PT
Terms of Use                                                                                      May 2018
